{
  "name": "PA179",
  "questions": [
    {
      "correct": ["Temporary, Change driving, Uncertain, Unique"],
      "wrong": [
        "Repetitive, Stable, Linear, Event driven",
        "Permanent, Simple, Flexible, Task driven"
      ],
      "question": "1. What are the main characteristics of a project?"
    },
    {
      "correct": ["Time, Cost, Scope"],
      "wrong": ["Risk, Quality, Procurement", "Plan, Change, Progress"],
      "question": "2. What are the usual dimensions of project manager’s triple constraint?"
    },
    {
      "correct": ["To add value to business", "To fulfil strategic goals"],
      "wrong": ["To create a unique product"],
      "question": "3. What is the aim of Project Portfolio?"
    },
    {
      "correct": ["Flow chart."],
      "wrong": ["Gantt chart.", "Use case diagram."],
      "question": "4. A process is best visualized with:"
    },
    {
      "correct": ["Manage by exceptions"],
      "wrong": ["Continued business justification", "Manage by stages"],
      "question": "5. Which PRINCE2 principle implies referring exceeded tolerances up next management level ?"
    },
    {
      "correct": ["Organization"],
      "wrong": ["Business Case", "Progress"],
      "question": "6. Which PRINCE2 theme addresses the need to identify stakeholders?"
    },
    {
      "correct": ["Initiating a project"],
      "wrong": ["Starting up a project", "Controlling a stage"],
      "question": "7. Which PRINCE2 process is dedicated to creating a Project Plan?"
    },
    {
      "correct": [
        "A project where comprehensive reporting is required",
        "A project team that requires firm control",
        "Entry-level project managers"
      ],
      "wrong": [],
      "question": "8. Which of these is PRINCE2 suitable for?"
    },
    {
      "correct": [
        "Integration, Scope, Schedule, Cost",
        "Quality, Communications, Risk, Procurement"
      ],
      "wrong": ["Business Case, Process, Progress, Talent"],
      "question": "9. PMBOK’s Knowledge areas include:"
    },
    {
      "correct": [
        "Process inputs",
        "Process tools and techniques",
        "Process outputs"
      ],
      "wrong": [],
      "question": "10. In PMBOK, every process definition includes:"
    },
    {
      "correct": ["Procurement"],
      "wrong": ["Scope", "Communications"],
      "question": "11. In PMBOK, which Knowledge area is dedicated to selecting and contracting outsourced products?"
    },
    {
      "correct": ["A handbook on different knowledge areas"],
      "wrong": [
        "A step-by-step method to follow",
        "A guide to project manager’s competencies"
      ],
      "question": "12. PMBOK is best used as:"
    },
    {
      "correct": ["Knowledge, skills and abilities"],
      "wrong": [
        "Wisdom, creativity and understanding",
        "Intelligence, information and experience"
      ],
      "question": "13. A competence is an application of:"
    },
    {
      "correct": [
        "Governance structures and processes, Compliance standards and regulations, Strategy",
        "Strategy, Power and interest, Culture and Values"
      ],
      "wrong": ["Quality, Change and transformation, Time"],
      "question": "14. ICB’s perspective competencies include:"
    },
    {
      "correct": [
        "Personal communication, Conflict and crisis, Resourcefulness",
        "Negotiation, Self-reflection and self-management, Teamwork",
        "Leadership, Relations and engagement, Results orientation"
      ],
      "wrong": [],
      "question": "15. ICB’s people competencies include:"
    },
    {
      "correct": ["Individual Competence Baseline"],
      "wrong": [
        "International Competence Baseline",
        "International Confidence Baseline"
      ],
      "question": "16. What does ICB stand for?"
    },
    {
      "correct": ["Increased need for risk management"],
      "wrong": [
        "Stability of resources",
        "Frequent unplanned requirements changes"
      ],
      "question": "17. What are the specifics of IT projects?"
    },
    {
      "correct": [
        "It helps us understand what service we’re creating or substantially changing"
      ],
      "wrong": [
        "It helps us determine who will run and monitor our project’s output",
        "It helps us evaluate our project’s risks"
      ],
      "question": "18. How is the ITIL Service Strategy process useful with regards to IT project management?"
    },
    {
      "correct": [
        "It is iterative and thus allows for changes later in the project"
      ],
      "wrong": [
        "It is straightforward and easy to implement",
        "Spiral model is not suitable for SW development"
      ],
      "question": "19. Why is spiral lifecycle model more suitable for SW development?"
    },
    {
      "correct": ["Focus on people"],
      "wrong": ["Thorough upfront planning", "Focus on processes"],
      "question": "20. What is typical in agile development?"
    },
    {
      "correct": ["Risk driven", "Iterative and incremental"],
      "wrong": ["Linear"],
      "question": "21. What are the characteristics of UP?"
    },
    {
      "correct": [
        "Business Modelling, Analysis, Requirements and Design, Implementation, Test, Deployment"
      ],
      "wrong": [
        "Business Modelling, Requirements, Implementation, Test, Deployment",
        "Inception, Elaboration, Construction, Transition"
      ],
      "question": "22. What are the possible workflows of each iteration?"
    },
    {
      "correct": ["Collect requirements", "Create baseline architecture"],
      "wrong": ["Test operational capability"],
      "question": "23. The Elaboration phase’s goals are:"
    },
    {
      "correct": ["Use case diagram"],
      "wrong": ["Class diagram", "Activity diagram"],
      "question": "24. Which type of UML diagram is most suitable for modelling requirements?"
    },
    {
      "correct": ["Managing the SCRUM process"],
      "wrong": ["Communication", "Delivering the product"],
      "question": "25. What is the core responsibility of Scrum Master?"
    },
    {
      "correct": ["Product Owner"],
      "wrong": ["Scrum Master", "Team of Developers"],
      "question": "26. Who is responsible for items in Product Backlog?"
    },
    {
      "correct": [
        "It should not be longer than one month",
        "It ends with the release of usable increment"
      ],
      "wrong": ["It includes development of all Product Backlog items"],
      "question": "27. What are the characteristics of SPRINT?"
    },
    {
      "correct": [
        "Process that allows early delivery of a usable product",
        "Iterative and incremental SW development framework."
      ],
      "wrong": ["Predictive SW development framework"],
      "question": "28. What is a SCRUM?"
    },
    {
      "correct": [
        "Project manager needs comprehensive method to follow",
        "The company’s culture requires comprehensive reporting"
      ],
      "wrong": ["Bureaucratic overload is not welcome"],
      "question": "29. PRINCE2 is the right choice of standard when:"
    },
    {
      "correct": [
        "Exact requirements are not known upfront",
        "Time to market is key factor"
      ],
      "wrong": ["The managed team is distributed across various locations"],
      "question": "30. SCRUM is the right choice of standard when:"
    },
    {
      "correct": [
        "The use of soft skills is crucial for the project’s success"
      ],
      "wrong": [
        "Project manager has little experience",
        "Project manager needs comprehensive method to follow"
      ],
      "question": "31. IPMA is the right choice of standard when:"
    },
    {
      "correct": [
        "Team experience, skills and collaboration",
        "Project’s domain, scale and requirements",
        "Advantages and limitations of the standard in consideration"
      ],
      "wrong": [],
      "question": "32. What needs to be taken into consideration when choosing appropriate standard for the project?"
    },
    {
      "correct": [
        "Welcome changing requirements, even late in delivery",
        "Build projects around motivated individuals"
      ],
      "wrong": ["Always stick to the plan."],
      "question": "33. Which of these are principles of agile SW development?"
    },
    {
      "correct": ["Coaching"],
      "wrong": ["Directive", "Bureaucratic"],
      "question": "34. Which approach is typical for agile project manager?"
    },
    {
      "correct": ["Product description", "Business case"],
      "wrong": ["Detailed quality management plan"],
      "question": "35. Which of these are usually included in Project charter?"
    },
    {
      "correct": ["Finish-to-start (FS)"],
      "wrong": ["Start-to-start (SS)", "Finish-to-finish (FF)"],
      "question": "36. Choose correct PDM relationship for this sequence of activities: „Testing of Component 1 cannot start until build of Component 1 has finished.“"
    },
    {
      "correct": ["New technologies", "Dependencies", "New suppliers"],
      "wrong": [],
      "question": "37. What are common sources of risks?"
    },
    {
      "correct": ["Probability and Impact"],
      "wrong": ["Duration and Quality", "Responsibility and participation"],
      "question": "38. Which two dimensions are estimated when assessing risks?"
    },
    {
      "correct": ["Reduce", "Transfer"],
      "wrong": ["Run"],
      "question": "39. Which of these are risk responses?"
    },
    {
      "correct": ["Shift possible impact to a third party"],
      "wrong": ["Avoid risk completely", "Nothing"],
      "question": "40. What do we do when transferring risks?"
    },
    {
      "correct": [
        "Everything that is required for Product backlog item or Increment completion."
      ],
      "wrong": [
        "Plan for the next Sprint.",
        "Meeting held at the beginning of Sprint."
      ],
      "question": "41. What is Definition of Done?"
    },
    {
      "correct": ["Remaining work."],
      "wrong": ["Remaining days of project.", "Top 10 to-do for today."],
      "question": "42. What does a Burndown chart display?"
    },
    {
      "correct": [
        "To forecast how long it will take to deliver items from Sprint or Product backlog.",
        "To better understand quality of the process."
      ],
      "wrong": ["To predict customer’s satisfaction."],
      "question": "43. Why do we count Team velocity?"
    },
    {
      "correct": ["Sprint retrospective", "Definition of done", "User stories"],
      "wrong": [],
      "question": "44. Which of these are built-in SCRUM measures for managing quality?"
    },
    {
      "correct": ["Description of a system feature."],
      "wrong": [
        "List of tasks to be done during the Sprint.",
        "A product-related report from the user."
      ],
      "question": "45. What is a user story?"
    },
    {
      "correct": [
        "They help define User story implementation boundaries.",
        "They serve as a baseline for functional testing."
      ],
      "wrong": ["They specify risks related to user story."],
      "question": "46. What are the advantages of adding acceptance criteria to User stories?"
    },
    {
      "correct": [
        "A metric of potential team effort to implement a User story."
      ],
      "wrong": [
        "Benefit points for achieving estimated financial budget.",
        "Agile tool for describing requirements."
      ],
      "question": "47. What are story points?"
    },
    {
      "correct": ["The amount of risk removed.", "Value to customer."],
      "wrong": ["What developers had for breakfast."],
      "question": "48. What should be considered when prioritizing the Product backlog?"
    },
    {
      "correct": ["Sprint Backlog"],
      "wrong": ["Sprint Goal", "One process improvement"],
      "question": "49. What are the main outcomes of Sprint review meeting?"
    },
    {
      "correct": [
        "An aggregate contribution of developing current Sprint’s user stories"
      ],
      "wrong": [
        "Total amount of team effort to fully implement a user story",
        "Clear-language description of a system feature"
      ],
      "question": "50. What is a Sprint goal?"
    },
    {
      "correct": [
        "What did I do yesterday?",
        "Did I see any obstructions/ blocking issues?"
      ],
      "wrong": ["What did I have for breakfast?"],
      "question": "51. Which of these questions are answered at Daily SCRUM meeting?"
    },
    {
      "correct": ["To review Product Backlog", "To inspect Increment"],
      "wrong": ["To inspect current Sprint’s relationships"],
      "question": "52. Why does the team hold a Sprint Review?"
    },
    {
      "correct": ["Act calm", "Listen actively"],
      "wrong": ["Make tasteless jokes"],
      "question": "53. Which of these are conflict deescalation techniques?"
    },
    {
      "correct": [
        "Other feature will not get developed",
        "Risk register will change"
      ],
      "wrong": ["Contract will have to be changed"],
      "question": "54. Which of these could be a consequence of adding an item to Product Backlog?"
    },
    {
      "correct": ["At the end of last Sprint"],
      "wrong": [
        "When all user stories from the Product Backlog have been implemented",
        "With the release of last increment"
      ],
      "question": "55. When is the product considered fully released?"
    },
    {
      "correct": [
        "To learn from successes and failures",
        "To review a completed project"
      ],
      "wrong": ["To plan for next project"],
      "question": "56. Why is Project Retrospective meeting being held?"
    },
    {
      "correct": [
        "A foundation document upon which the Project Board decides to proceed."
      ],
      "wrong": [
        "List of product requirements from the customer.",
        "Short meeting at the beginning of the project."
      ],
      "question": "57. In PRINCE2, what is a Project Brief?"
    },
    {
      "correct": ["Senior user", "Executive"],
      "wrong": ["QA Engineer"],
      "question": "58. Which of these roles are a part of the Project Board?"
    },
    {
      "correct": [
        "Project management standards",
        "Corporate or programme strategies",
        "External dependencies and prerequisites to the project"
      ],
      "wrong": [],
      "question": "59. What needs to be taken into consideration when defining management approach?"
    },
    {
      "correct": [
        "Milestones",
        "Estimated duration of activities",
        "Roles and responsibilities"
      ],
      "wrong": [],
      "question": "60. What needs to be defined in the Next stage plan?"
    },
    {
      "correct": ["Work Package"],
      "wrong": ["Unimportant deliverable", "User story"],
      "question": "61. What do we call the lowest level of Work Breakdown Structure?"
    },
    {
      "correct": ["Technique for evaluating time effort"],
      "wrong": [
        "Technique for calculating critical path",
        "Product description"
      ],
      "question": "62. What is PERT?"
    },
    {
      "correct": ["Start and end points", "Dependencies"],
      "wrong": ["Responsibility"],
      "question": "63. What do we need to know about an activity in order to calculate Critical path?"
    },
    {
      "correct": [
        "Review of team performance",
        "Summary of current issues and risks"
      ],
      "wrong": ["Detailed plan for next stage"],
      "question": "64. Which of these do we include in End stage report?"
    },
    {
      "correct": [
        "All major technical risks get resolved early",
        "Organizing teams around architecture minimizes communication overload"
      ],
      "wrong": ["There are no advantages to this approach"],
      "question": "65. What are the advantages of planning a project around robust architecture?"
    },
    {
      "correct": [
        "A plan that usually follows an Exception report",
        "A plan of recovery from exceeded project’s tolerances"
      ],
      "wrong": ["A report of current progress"],
      "question": "66. What is an exception plan?"
    },
    {
      "correct": ["Team manager"],
      "wrong": ["Executive", "Configurations manager"],
      "question": "67. According to PRINCE2, who manages the product delivery?"
    },
    {
      "correct": ["Time", "Scope", "Cost"],
      "wrong": [],
      "question": "68. Which of these project’s variables can be affected by a request for change?"
    },
    {
      "correct": [
        "Creating documentation",
        "Beta testing with subset of users",
        "Providing user’s training"
      ],
      "wrong": [],
      "question": "69. What are the usual activities in UP’s Transition phase?"
    },
    {
      "correct": [
        "Review of team performance",
        "Benefits achieved to date",
        "Summary of project performance"
      ],
      "wrong": [],
      "question": "70. Which of these are included in End project report?"
    },
    {
      "correct": [
        "To embed positive lessons in the organization’s way of working",
        "To avoid negative experience in future projects"
      ],
      "wrong": ["To test product features"],
      "question": "71. What is the purpose of lessons report?"
    },
    {
      "correct": [
        "Creating End project report",
        "Requesting and obtaining Acceptance records"
      ],
      "wrong": ["Planning the next project"],
      "question": "72. Which of these activities are a part of a PRINCE2 Closing phase?"
    }
  ]
}
